[Music]
welcome back to the channel
this time we're going to do haagen-dazs
belgian chocolate so this is this
actually
is my first memory of eating carkindars
down windsor high street when i was
visiting my mate queen
i mean i must have been young teenager
something like my aunt
we went down there and had a belgian
chocolate milkshake from there
and since then it's always been my
favorite hogan does flavor so
i thought we could recreate it on here
it's actually quite a simple recipe
we're actually making this video
immediately after the
fish food recipe which i'll link to up
here
it's the same basic base so all your
ingredients are in the description below
put them all in a pot on the hob heat it
up until the sugar is dissolved
and then add 100 grams of really high
quality
belgian chocolate now you can just use
the likes of this which is absolutely
fine
it's your box standard supermarket
cooking belgian chocolate but
because we've got them here i've
actually used
those we've got lots of different types
of those but 70
or higher ideally you don't want to go
too high so anything above kind of like
85 might get a bit bitter
you put that into into your base while
it's on the hob
give it a good stir make sure the
chocolate's all melted get your little
tiny whisk in there
and then once it's all dissolved and
amalgamated together take it off the hob
and put it in the fridge now our base
has been in the fridge for 24 hours
and 20 minutes ago like in the fishery
recipe i took the base out and i mixed
in
the skimmed milk powder and that acts as
a stabilizer for this as it's an eggless
base
there are lots of other stabilizers you
can use but for ease this one works
just as well as all the other fancy ones
so once you've done that
we can actually just crack on and make
it
[Music]
okay so once your base has come out of
the fridge and you're ready to churn
and you can put it straight in one thing
i wanted to mention is
a i put two tablespoons of organic
dark cocoa powder into the mix as well
that just creates a really luxurious
finish to this belgian chocolate ice
cream and
once you've chopped your chocolate that
you're going to use as an
add-in to this keep it in the fridge or
freezer
until the last couple of minutes are
churning so now
we'll just put the base straight into
the mix
again when you use the milk powder as a
stabilizer
you'll need you'll get this little
bubble top on top of your mix just stir
that back in
and that is the milk solids coming to
the top again
it's important to use no fat or
worst case low fat milk powder
because you don't want to increase the
fat content you just want to increase
the solids content
pour that into your machine
and then get it going and we'll see you
in about half an hour
[Music]
so once your ice cream's churned it
really is a simple case of
putting it in your tub this is my design
tub it's not as good as my wife as you
can see but
i do my best and then put it in the
freezer
it's a really simple recipe to make this
one and
as long as you follow the numbers that
i've put in the description
you really can't go wrong
so that's four hours ish in the freezer
and we're gonna take a scoop of
both of these put on the plate and
compare the two the haagen-dazs
like i said this is a childhood favorite
of mine
it's um it really brought back brings
back memories of
of going out with my aunt and getting a
milkshake from from windsor
it's it's not a difficult flavor to
recreate
and you can do it really cheaply too
i mean haagen-dazs is expensive like all
the the big brands you know the big
luxury ice creams
in england it's about five pounds a pot
maybe a bit more depends on where you
buy it
you can actually make this for less than
two pounds a pot
and you can just use any dark belgian
chocolate it doesn't have to be fancy
stuff just supermarkets home will do
absolutely fine so
let's get some help
[Music]
so here we go let's uh let's give these
uh let's give these a try the
original belgian haagen-dazs belgian
chocolate
it's really good this one it's very
creamy
very smooth texture loads and loads of
little tiny little chocolate chips right
there
this is our version
same color same consistency
hmm
[Music]
that tastes identical
to the hardness identical
the only difference is the chocolate
i've not cut it small enough i'm not
i've not chopped it small enough
they probably grate theirs but if i
grate mine now
it just won't be the same so the smaller
you can get your chocolate
flex using the recipe that is in the
description below
you are going to get an identical ice
cream to the haagen-dazs belgian
chocolate so
all in all really really successful
ice cream this one and i hope you enjoy
the rather comical little decoration
thanks very much for watching